Contact

akahate@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/atulkahate (LinkedIn)

Atul Kahate

IT-Professional, Author and Visiting Faculty of Computer Science Pune, Maharashtra, India

Summary

Currently working as a Freelance Computer Science Visiting Faculty, mainly at C-DAC, Pune and DESPU for a range of subjects since April 2022.

Have worked with many IT companies (Syntel, American Express, Deutsche Bank, LTI, Oracle), playing roles ranging from Software Developer to Head of Technology Practice.

Authored over 80 books.

Passionate about technology.

Visiting Faculty at Symbiosis from 2001 to 2022.

Experience

C-DAC ACTS - Pune
Computer Science Trainer at C-DAC, Pune
April 2022 - Present (3 years 4 months)
Pune, Maharashtra, India

Currently teaching: AI, NLP, CV, Gen AI, Cloud Programming, Cloud Concepts and Hands-on (AWS, GCP, Azure), Microservices using Spring Boot and Python Flask, Data Warehousing and Data Mining, Data Analytics using Python, Machine Learning, Big Data Analytics, Hadoop, Blockchain, Web Analytics, DevOps (Gradle, Git, Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins), Apache Spark, Apache Kafka, Cryptography/PKI, Data Visualization using Power BI/Tableau, CUDA GPU Programming, Snowflake, dbt

Experience of working/teaching:

Web Technologies (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JSP/Servlets, PHP, Ajax, Node.JS. Angular), Digital Business, Big Data Analytics (Hadoop, MapReduce, Pig, Spark, Apache Airflow), Cryptography, Network Security, Computer Networks and TCP/IP, Operating Systems, Blockchain, NoSQL/MongoDB,

Programming Languages (C, C++, Java, Python, SQL), Web Analytics, Machine Learning, IBM Mainframe (COBOL, CICS, VSAM, JCL, DB2, IMS), Wix, Perl, Python/Flask, Data Warehousing, Apache Kafka, Spring Boot, DevOps (Docker, Kubernetes), Google Cloud Platform (GCP)

Various
Book Author
January 2000 - Present (25 years 7 months)

(Oracle)
Consulting Practice Director, Technology Head, Delivery Head, Project Manager, Software Engineer

Syntel, American Express, Deutsche Bank, L&T Infotech, i-flex

June 1995 - November 2022 (27 years 6 months)

SYMBIOSIS INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY

Visiting Faculty of Computer Science January 2001 - October 2022 (21 years 10 months) Pune, Maharashtra, India

Taught a number of technical subjects to MSc, MBA, and BCA students for over 20 years.

Education

Shivaji University BSc (Statistics) and MBA